SUSAN RENAUD

PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

Le Wagon London Coding Bootcamp

July 2019 - Sep 2019

 9-week intensive full-stack coding bootcamp learning UI/UX, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku, Ruby on Rails.

Projects:

- <u>Two-Wheeler</u> Collaborated with another developer to design and implement a bike rental platform built using Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS/SCSS, Bootstrap, Mapbox and Cloudinary APIs, GitHub and Heroku.
- <u>Losty!</u> In a group of two people, developed a lost and found web application where people who lose things can connect to those who have found them. This project has a fully functional search bar and messaging system, and was built using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, different APIs, GitHub and Heroku.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Applied Behavior Learning Center

Apr 2016 - Oct 2018

Team Lead Behavioral Therapist

- Implemented Applied Behavior Analysis techniques in 1:1 therapy sessions to children ages 2-13 diagnosed with Autism Spectrum Disorders.
- Performed client-specific programs and protocols intended to build a variety of skills. These include self help skills, communication and social skills, emotional regulation and attending, and decrease targeted challenging behaviors.
- Managed client records, data and materials; responsible for making sure behavioral therapists on clients' teams implemented therapy and programs correctly.
- Collected, managed and analyzed various types of client data.

Frankino Lab - University of Houston

May 2013 - Dec 2015

Lab Manager

- Conducted an original experiment testing whether the flight ability of Drosophila melanogaster affects survival in the presence of a predator, and whether effects hold across different temperatures.
- Organized day to day lab tasks and activities, including maintenance of stocks and implementation of experiments.
- Trained lab members in lab protocols, best practices, and experiment implementation procedures.
- Arranged and managed work schedules for up to eight student workers at a time.

BOUNCE (Behavior Opportunities Uniting Counseling Aug 2015 - Dec 2015 and Education)

Intern

- Collaborated with group members to administer nutrition/healthy lifestyle classes at elementary schools to girls aged 9-14.
- Assisted with administering surveys, data collection, data entry, and data management including use of Qualtrics and Excel.

EDUCATION

University of HoustonBachelor of Science in Psychology and Public Health Magna Cum Laude

Dec 2015

SUMMARY

I am a Full-Stack Developer | UX Researcher | Data Analyst looking to utilize my newly acquired programming skills while leveraging my previous experience. I chose to study psychology and public health in university because I wanted to make a positive impact on the world. This passion along with my interest in research and data analytics led me to work in Applied Behavior Analysis - where my latent interest in technology steadily grew. After nearly three years, that interest became fully realized, and I knew I needed a change. After taking some time off, I decided to attend Le Wagon London Bootcamp to learn full-stack web development. I am confident that the skills I gained there will help me have a bigger impact on an increasingly digital world.

SKILLSET

- Web Development
 - Ruby/Ruby on Rails
 - HTML
 - CSS/SCSS
 - JavaScript
 - UI/UX Design
 - Python
 - MVC Framework
- Databases
 - SQL
- Research
 - UX Research
 - Public Health
 - Biology
- Management/Team Leadership
- Applied Behavior Analysis

CONTACT



1-832-260-4278



serenaud89@gmail.com



susan-renaud.com



susan-renaud



susanelizabethrenaud